Okay. Let's get back to what we really want to talk about, PCA.
Ok下面回到我们真正要讨论的话题——PCA
In a nutshell, what is PCA?
什么是 PCA？
PCA is a series of calculations that gives us a new and special basis for our data.
PCA 是一系列从数据中发现新的特殊基的运算
Why is it special?
为何是特殊的基？
Well, the first dimension is the dimension
因为沿着第一个维度的
along which the data points are the most spread out,
数据点非常的分散
we say they have the most variance along this dimension.
也就是沿着这个维度的方差最大
What do we mean exactly?
到底是什么意思？
We mean that, if we start with a dataset and we consider
假设有一个数据集 并且在二维平面里
a new axis in the 2D plane represented by this line through the origin,
有一个新的坐标轴 由这个穿过原点的直线表示
then we find the coordinates of our points along this new axis
我们将数据点按照最短的路径投射到新的坐标轴上
by projecting them by the shortest path to the new axis.
并算出这些点沿着新坐标轴的坐标
Consider the variance or spread of this set of coordinates along the line.
思考下沿着这条线的这组坐标的方差或分散性
When we do PCA or trying to choose our new axis in
在进行主成分分析时 我们尝试找到一条新的坐标轴
such a way that the new coordinates are as spread
使新的坐标尽可能分散
out as possible or have maximum variance,
或者方差最大化
it turns out that the choice of line,
结果发现这条线
where the coordinates are most spread out,
即让坐标最为分散的线
is also the choice of line that minimizes
也是让每个坐标
the perpendicular distance of each coordinate to the line.
距离这条线垂直距离最短的线
We say that the basis minimizes reconstruction error.
我们称之为基向量能够最小化重构误差
Maximizing variance and minimizing reconstruction error go hand in hand.
最大化方差和最小化重构误差是紧密相关的
The squared distance from the origin to the projection,
从原点到投射点的距离的平方
plus the squared distance from the projection to the point,
加上从投射点到这个点的距离的平方
equals the squared distance from the origin to the point,
等于从原点到这个点的距离的平方
this is just the Pythagorean theorem.
这就是勾股定理
So, when you change the orientation of the line,
所以当你改变这条线的方向时
if one increases the other must decrease.
一个距离增大了 另一个肯定会缩小
The orientation of the line chosen by PCA is the one that
PCA 所选的这条线的方向
maximizes the squared distances along the line
能够最大化所有点
for all points and simultaneously minimizes
沿着这条线的距离的平方
the squared perpendicular distances to the line for all points.
同时能够最小化所有点到这条线的垂直距离的平方
This is how we find the first basis direction.
我们通过这种方式找到第一个基向量的方向
The next basis direction must be perpendicular or orthogonal to the first.
第二个基向量的方向必须与第一个基向量垂直或正交
In our little example,
在这个小示例中
there is only one choice for this dimension,
只有一种选择
because we are working in a two-dimensional space.
因为我们处在二维空间里
But if we were working in a higher-dimensional space,
但是如果数据处于更高维度的空间
the requirement for the next basis direction would be that it be
那么第二个基向量的方向
orthogonal to the first and also maximize
必须与第一个基向量正交
the variance of the points along that dimension and so
同时能够最大化数据点沿着该维度的方差
on until we have as many new dimensions as we had dimensions to start with.
以此类推 直到新的维度与数据的维度一样多
So, if we had data in four dimensions,
所以 如果数据有四个维度
PCA would give us four new axes.
那么 PCA 会找到四条新的坐标轴